Semel, Elisabeth; Collection apap332
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Elisabeth Semel Papers
1977-2012
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Semel, Elisabeth A.
apap332
8.66 cubic ft.
Elisabeth Semel's papers primarily consist of articles published from the 1990s to early 2000s used by Semel in her research and work concerning the death penalty.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Elisabeth Semel in 2012.
Biographical History
Elisabeth A. Semel began her law career when she graduated from the School of Law at the University of California, Davis in 1975. She practiced privately from 1980 to 1997, working solo until she created Semel and Feldman as a partner in 1983. In 1997 she began serving as the director of the American Bar Association Death Penalty Representation Project in Washington, D.C., where she remained until 2001.
When Semel left D.C., she returned to California to become an Acting Clinical Professor at Law at Berkeley Law. In 2005 she became the first director of the Berkeley Law Death Penalty Clinic, and a Clinical Professor at Law, positions that she holds today. At the Clinic, Semel supervises students who represent clients facing the death penalty during all stages of the proceedings. Her research focuses on the role of race in the administration of the death penalty, and includes representation in juries.
Over the course of her career, Semel has published many articles and opinion pieces on the subject of the death penalty and related criminal justice topics. She often comments in mainstream media on current death penalty topics and issues, particularly the rights of those facing a death sentence. She has received several awards including the Outstanding Legal Service Award from the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty in 2008, and most recently the Death Penalty Focus Abolition Award in 2011.
Scope and Contents
Semel's papers, for the most part, contain articles about the death penalty published over the last few decades. The articles cover either specific state or federal cases, or issues related to the death penalty such as race, mental illness, or public opinion. The collection also includes court transcripts from select cases, and a couple of surveys performed regarding the death penalty.
The collection has been divided into two series; one for specific cases arranged by state and the other for topics related to the death penalty. Within Series 1, all federal cases have been placed under "Federal" first, then arranged alphabetically by the title of the file.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series: Cases and Issues and Topics.
Death Penalty; Capital punishment; Discrimination in capital punishment; Articles; Criminal court records; Transcripts; Semel, Elisabeth A.
- Cases and Surveys, 1981-2012; 1; 5.66 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains articles pertaining to specific cases, arranged by state and then by last name of the case subject. The list includes the District of Columbia and is missing four states: Alaska, North Dakota, West Virginia, and Wyoming. California is the most represented, carrying more extensive materials in the cases of Robert Alton Harris, Michael Morales, and Darrell "Young Elk" Rich. Similarly, Texas contains more material for Juan Garza and Thomas Miller-El. Federal cases are filed under "Federal" and then arranged alphabetically from there with the section consisting mainly of death penalty surveys, material on Timothy McVeigh, and a few other federal cases. Various surveys that have been conducted on the death penalty are included along with the articles.
  - ACLU - Alabama Death Penalty Study, October, 2005 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 1)
  - ACLU - The Hidden Death Tax, Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 2)
  - ACLU - Death by Geography, Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 3)
  - Alabama - Anniston Star Series, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 4)
  - Alabama - 2000-2001, 1999-2001; 2004; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 5)
  - Alabama - 2002-2003, 2002-2004 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 6)
  - Alabama - 2004, 2004-2006 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 7)
  - Alabama - 2005-2009, 2005-2008; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 8)
  - Arizona, 1997; 2000-2004; 2007; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 9)
  - Arkansas, 1997; 1999; 2001-2002; 2004; 2007 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 10)
  - Bakersfield Californian - Special Report, December, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 11)
  - Birmingham News - Death Penalty Series, November, 2005 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 12)
  - California - Allen, Clarence Ray, 2005-2006 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 13)
  - California - Babbitt, Manny, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 14)
  - California - Beardslee, Donald, 2004-2005 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 15)
  - California - Death Penalty, Through 1999, 1997-2001; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 16)
  - California - Death Penalty, 2000-2002; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 17)
  - California - Death Penalty, 2003, 2000; 2003-2004 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 18)
  - California - Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 19)
  - California - Death Penalty, 2005-2007, 2005-2008 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 20)
  - California - Death Penalty Statistics, 1993; 1995-1996; 2002; 2006-2008; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 21)
  - California - Death Row, San Quentin, 2003; 2005-2008 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 22)
  - California - Diaz, Robert, Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 23)
  - California - Filings, Kevin Cooper, 2001; 2004-2005 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 24)
  - California - Gay, Kenneth, 2000 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 25)
  - California - Governor's Race, 2002 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 26)
  - California - Habeas Corpus Resource Center, 1994; 1996-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 27)
  - California - Harris, Robert Alton, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 28)
  - California - Harris, Anti-Death Penalty Opinion, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 29)
  - California - Harris, Defense Attorneys, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 30)
  - California - Harris, European Reaction, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 31)
  - California - Harris, Execution, 1992-1995; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 32)
  - California - Harris, Federal Courts, 1981; 1990; 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 33)
  - California - Harris, Letters to the Editor, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 34)
  - California - Harris, Personal Background, 1990; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 35)
  - California - Harris, Pro-Death Penalty Opinion, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 36)
  - California - Harris, Protestors/Demonstration, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 37)
  - California - Harris, Psychiatric Letter to Wilson, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 38)
  - California - Harris, Fetal Alcohol Syndrome-Religious Reaction, Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 39)
  - California - Harris, Sevilla, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 40)
  - California - Harris, State Court, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 41)
  - California - Harris, Victims, Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 42)
  - California - Harris, Wilson, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 43)
  - California - Kelly, Horace, 1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 44)
  - California - Mason, David vs. Vaquez, 1993; 2001 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 45)
  - California - Massie, Robert, 2001 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 46)
  - California - Mental Retardation Bill, 2001-2002; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 47)
  - California - Morales, Michael-Clemency, 2006 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 48)
  - California - Morales, Michael-Habeas, 2004 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 49)
  - California - Morales, Lethal Injection News Articles, 2006-2007 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 50)
  - California - Morales, Lethal Injection Litigation, 2006-2007 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 51)
  - California - Siripongs, Jay, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 52)
  - California - State Bar Capital Appeals Report, 1981; 1990-1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 53)
  - California - Stolen Justice Mercury, Criminal Justice Series, 2006 (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 54)
  - California - Supreme Court, 1992-1993; 1995; 2000-2002; 2004-2008; Undated (Box 1 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 55)
  - California - Rich, Darrell Keith (1 of 2), 1988; 1997; 1999 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 1)
  - California - Rich, Darrell Keith (2 of 2), 1988; 1997; 1999 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 2)
  - California - Rich, Darrell "Young Elk", 2000 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 3)
  - California - Rich, Darrell-Media, 2000; Undated (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 4)
  - California - Thompson, Thomas, 1996-1998; Undated (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 5)
  - California - Williams, Keith, 1996 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 6)
  - California - Williams, Stanley, 2000; 2003; 2005 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 7)
  - Colorado, 1997; 2000-2003; 2007; Undated (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 8)
  - Connecticut, 1999; 2001-2002; 2004-2005; 2007 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 9)
  - District of Columbia, 2000-2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 10)
  - Delaware, 2000-2004; 2006 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 11)
  - Federal - Ashcroft Report, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 12)
  - Federal - Ashcroft Testimony, June, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 13)
  - Federal - Ashcroft June Hearing and Testimony, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 14)
  - Federal - Ashcroft Testimonies, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 15)
  - Federal - Ashcroft E-mails, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 16)
  - Federal - Death Penalty Survey (1 of 3), 2000 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 17)
  - Federal - Death Penalty Survey (2 of 3), 2000 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 18)
  - Federal - Death Penalty Survey (3 of 3), 2000 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 19)
  - Federal - Death Penalty Before 2001, 1997-2000; Undated (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 20)
  - Federal - Death Penalty (1 of 2), 2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 21)
  - Federal - Death Penalty (2 of 2), 2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 22)
  - Federal - Death Penalty, 2002 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 23)
  - Federal - Death Penalty, 2003 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 24)
  - Federal - Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 25)
  - Federal - Death Penalty, 2005-2007 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 26)
  - Federal - Kazcynski, Ted, 1998-1999; 2001; Undated (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 27)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Anti, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 28)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Timothy-Clippings (1 of 2), 2001-2002; 2004; Undated (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 29)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Timothy-Clippings (2 of 2), 2001-2002; 2004; Undated (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 30)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Pleadings May-June, 2001; Undated (Box 2 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 31)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Pleadings (1 of 2), 1996-1998 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 1)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Pleadings (2 of 2), 1996-1998 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 2)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Pro, 2001 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 3)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Trial (1 of 4), 1997; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 4)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Trial (2 of 4), 1997; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 5)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Trial (3 of 4), 1997; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 6)
  - Federal - McVeigh, Trial (4 of 4), 1997; 1999-2001; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 7)
  - Federal - Missaoui, 2002 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 8)
  - Federal - Nichols,Terry, 1997-2001 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 9)
  - Federal - Quinones, 2002 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 10)
  - Florida - 1995-1997 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 11)
  - Florida - 1998 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 12)
  - Florida - 1999, 1999-2000 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 13)
  - Florida - 2000 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 14)
  - Florida - 2001 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 15)
  - Florida - 2002, 2002-2004 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 16)
  - Florida - 2003, 2001; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 17)
  - Florida - 2004-2007 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 18)
  - Georgia - The Atlanta Journal Constitution Series, 2007-2008; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 19)
  - Georgia - Through 2004, 1999-2003; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 20)
  - Georgia - 2007-2008, 2005 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 21)
  - Georgia - Moore, Billy, 1984; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 22)
  - Georgia - Williams, Alex, 2002 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 23)
  - Hawaii, 2003 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 24)
  - Idaho, 2000-2003; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 25)
  - Illinois - 2008-2009 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 26)
  - Illinois - Cases, 1991; 1996; 1998-2004; 2007; Undated (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 27)
  - Illinois - Chicago Tribune Death Penalty Series, 1999 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 28)
  - Illinois - Clemency, 2002-2003 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 29)
  - Illinois - Counsel, 1999-2002 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 30)
  - Illinois - Cruz, 1998-2002 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 31)
  - Illinois - Legislation, 2000-2003 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 32)
  - Illinois - Moratorium, 1999-2000; 2002; 2005 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 33)
  - Illinois - Opinions, 1999-2003 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 34)
  - Illinois - Porter, Anthony, 1999-2000; 2003 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 35)
  - Illinois - Ryan, 2001-2003 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 36)
  - Illinois - Ryan, Commission Report Press File, 2002; 2004 (Box 3 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 37)
  - Indiana, 1996; 2000-2005; 2007-2008 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 1)
  - Indiana Series - Other Lottery 2001, 2001-2002 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 2)
  - Iowa, 1998; 2001-2002 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 3)
  - Kansas, 2001; 2003; 2005; 2007 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 4)
  - Kentucky, 1997-1998; 2000-2004 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 5)
  - Louisiana, 1998-2005 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 6)
  - Maine, 2001 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 7)
  - Maryland - Pre 2003, 1991; 1997-1998; 2000-2004; Undated (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 8)
  - Maryland - 2003-2006, 2002-2005 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 9)
  - Maryland - 2007, 2007-2008 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 10)
  - Maryland - Colvin-El, 1999-2000; Undated (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 11)
  - Massachusetts, 1997; 2001; 2003-2007 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 12)
  - Michigan, 1997-2000; 2002; 2004 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 13)
  - Minnesota, 2000-2001; 2003 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 14)
  - Mississippi, 1997-2004; Undated (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 15)
  - Missouri, 1997-2002; 2006; Undated (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 16)
  - Missouri - Amrine, 2002-2004 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 17)
  - Missouri - Mease, Darrell, 1999 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 18)
  - Missouri - Richardson, Antonio, 2001; 2003; 2007 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 19)
  - Montana, 1999; Undated (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 20)
  - Nebraska, 1999-2003; 2005; 2007-2008 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 21)
  - Nebraska - Study, 2001 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 22)
  - Nevada, 2000-2004; Undated (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 23)
  - New Hampshire, 1998; 2000; 2004; 2007-2008 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 24)
  - New Jersey - Through 2004, 1997-2006 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 25)
  - New Jersey - 2006-2007, 2007-2008 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 26)
  - New Mexico, 2001-2004; 2007 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 27)
  - New York - Cases, 1996-2004; 2006 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 28)
  - New York - General, 1996; 1998-2008 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 29)
  - New York - Legislation, 1998-2005; 2007; Undated (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 30)
  - New York - Opinions, 1999-2007 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 31)
  - North Carolina - 2004-2006 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 32)
  - North Carolina - 2007, 2007-2008 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 33)
  - North Carolina - Cases, 1999-2001; 2003; 2005 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 34)
  - North Carolina - Counsel, 2002-2003; 2006 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 35)
  - North Carolina - General, 2000-2004; 2006 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 36)
  - North Carolina - Judges, 2002 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 37)
  - North Carolina - Legislation, 2000-2001; 2003-2004; 2006 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 38)
  - North Carolina - Moratorium, 2000-2003; 2007 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 39)
  - North Carolina - Opinions, 2000-2001 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 40)
  - Ohio, 2000-2007; Undated (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 41)
  - Oklahoma, 1993; 2000-2004; 2006-2007 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 42)
  - Oklahoma - Gilchrist, Joyce, 2001 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 43)
  - Oklahoma - Sellars, Sean, 1998-1999 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 44)
  - Oregon, 2000-2002; 2004 (Box 4 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 45)
  - Pennsylvania - 2000-2004, 1998-2004; Undated (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 1)
  - Pennsylvania - 2006-2008, 2007 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 2)
  - Rhode Island, 2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 3)
  - South Carolina - 2002, 1998-2002 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 4)
  - South Carolina - 2003, Undated (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 5)
  - South Carolina - 2004, 2006; Undated (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 6)
  - South Carolina - 2005-2006 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 7)
  - South Dakota, 2000; 2002 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 8)
  - Tennessee, 1999-2004; 2006-2007; Undated (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 9)
  - Tennessee - Death Penalty Series, July, 2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 10)
  - Texas - 2004, 2004-2005 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 11)
  - Texas - 2005-2006, 2004-2006; Undated (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 12)
  - Texas - 2007, 2007-2008 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 13)
  - Texas - Banks, Delma, 2003-2004 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 14)
  - Texas - Beazley, Napoleon, 2001-2002; Undated (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 15)
  - Texas - Burdine, Calvin, 2000-2003 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 16)
  - Texas - Cases, 1997-2005; 2012 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 17)
  - Texas - Counsel, 1998-2004; 2006 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 18)
  - Texas - Dallas Morning News, Batson Series August, 2005 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 19)
  - Texas - DeLuna, Chicago Tribune Innocence, 2006 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 20)
  - Texas - Faulder, 1997-1999 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 21)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Media List, 2000 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 22)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Reno/Department of Justice Articles, 2000 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 23)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Reno Press Statement, 2000-2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 24)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, White House Articles, 2000-2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 25)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles (1 of 2), 2000 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 26)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles (2 of 2), 2000 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 27)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Bush Articles, 2000-2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 28)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Bush Transcripts, 2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 29)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, Department of Justice Articles and Transcripts, 2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 30)
  - Texas - Garza Press Statements and News Articles, 2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 31)
  - Texas - General, 1997-2004 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 32)
  - Texas - Graham, Gary, 1998; 2000; Undated (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 33)
  - Texas - Houston Chronicle Series, 2001 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 34)
  - Texas - Legislation, 1999-2003 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 35)
  - Texas - McGinn, Ricky, 2000 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 36)
  - Texas - Mentally Retarded, 1999-2004 (Box 5 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 37)
  - Texas - Miller-El, Thomas News File, 2000-2004 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 1)
  - Texas - Miller-El, Thomas Media Round 2, 2004-2005 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 2)
  - Texas - Miller-El, Media Post 2005 Reversal, 2008 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 3)
  - Texas - News Stories, 2004 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 4)
  - Texas - Opinions, 1998-2005 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 5)
  - Texas - Penry, 1999-2001; 2003; Undated (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 6)
  - Texas - Robison, Larry, 1999-2000 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 7)
  - Texas - Rojas, Leonard, 2002-2003 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 8)
  - Texas - Tucker, Karla Faye, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 9)
  - Texas - Yates, Andrea, 2001-2002; 2005 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 10)
  - Utah, 2002-2004 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 11)
  - Vermont, 2001 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 12)
  - Virginia - Breard, Angel Francisco, 1998 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 13)
  - Virginia - Cases, 1997-2006 (Box 6 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 14)
  - Virginia - Coleman, Roger Keith, 1992; 2000-2003 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 1)
  - Virginia - General, 1997; 1999-2005; 2007 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 2)
  - Virginia - Jackson, Chauncey, 1998; 2000 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 3)
  - Virginia - Kasi, 1997-1999; 2002 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 4)
  - Virginia - Legislation, 1998; 2000-2002; 2007 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 5)
  - Virginia - Opinions, 2000-2004; 2008 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 6)
  - Virginia - Retardation, 2001-2003 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 7)
  - Virginia - Walton, Percy, 2006 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 8)
  - Virginia - Washington, Earl, 1994; 2000-2001 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 9)
  - Virginia - Williams, Terry, 1998-2000; Undated (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 10)
  - Virginia - Wright, Dwayne, 1998; Undated (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 11)
  - Washington, 2001-2003; 2007 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 12)
  - Washington - Seattle P-I Series, 2001 (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 13)
  - Wisconsin, 2003; Undated (Box 7 (1-Cases and Surveys), Folder 14)
- Issues and Topics, 1977-2009; 2; 3 cubic ft.